bighistoryproject.com 2015-09-15

# Big History Project Website Privacy Policy

Effective Date: June 8, 2015

#### 1\. PRIVACY NOTIFICATION

Big History Project, LLC (" **BHP** ") understands that online privacy is important and we are committed to protecting your privacy. Please read this policy regarding our privacy practices (" **Privacy Policy** ") before using the Site. When you access or use the Site, your information, including personal information, will be collected, transferred, processed, stored, and disclosed in accordance with this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy is part of and incorporated into the Terms of Use governing your use of the Site. Parts of the Terms of Use affect this Privacy Policy, so unless you have already done so, please review the Terms prior to using the Site. By accessing or registering for an account with the Site, you expressly consent to the collection, transfer, use, processing, and storage of your information, including personal information, as described in this Privacy Policy. Capitalized terms used but not defined in this Privacy Policy have the definitions provided in the Terms of Use. You can determine if any changes were made to this Privacy Policy by noting the date that the Privacy Policy was last updated. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE WITH THIS POLICY, YOU SHOULD NOT USE OR REGISTER FOR AN ACCOUNT ON THE SITE. 

IF YOU ARE A PARENT OR GUARDIAN AND YOU PROVIDE CONSENT FOR YOUR CHILD TO USE OR REGISTER FOR AN ACCOUNT WITH THE SITE, YOU ARE BOUND BY THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND OUR TERMS OF USE IN RESPECT TO YOUR CHILD's USE OF THE SITE.

#### 2\. CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY

BHP reserves the right to revise this Privacy Policy from time to time by updating this posting, with the new terms taking effect on the date of posting. You should periodically review this Privacy Policy to ensure that you are familiar with the most current version. Your continued use of the Site after the Effective Date posted above will constitute your acceptance of the updated Privacy Policy.

#### 3\. OUR INFORMATION COLLECTION PRACTICES 

**3.1 General.** When you visit the Site without creating an account, you can browse without submitting any personal information about yourself. We will, however, receive and store some non-personally-identifiable information about you. For example, we automatically receive and record information on our server logs from your browser including your IP address, browser type and language, referring/exit pages and URLs, other browser history, platform type, number of clicks, landing pages, cookie information, the pages you requested and viewed, the amount of time spent on particular pages, and the date and time. If you create an account, we will also collect some personally identifiable information from you, including your full name, a user name (email address) and password, and your email address. Student and teacher account holders must also submit information regarding educational institution affiliation, location, and grade level. BHP is an entity located in the United States and your personally identifiable information will be collected and stored in the United States by BHP and its third party service providers. 

**3.2 Automatically Collected Information.** Similar to other web sites, we will collect some information automatically and store it in log files, for example, through the use of "cookies" and other tracking mechanisms. This information does not identify you. This collection may include, but is not limited to, your IP address, browser type and language, referring/exit pages and URLs, other browser history, platform type, number of clicks, landing pages, cookie information, the pages you requested and viewed, the amount of time spent on particular pages, and the date and time. We collect this non-personally identifiable information in order to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer the Site. Your IP address is also used to help identify you and to gather broad demographic information. We may also use cookies, clear gifs, and log file information to: (a) store information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you visit the Site; (b) monitor aggregate metrics such as total number of visitors, pages viewed, etc.; and (c) track entries, submissions, and status in any interactive portion of the Site.

**3.3 Cookies.** A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user's computer for record-keeping purposes. Our third-party analytics providers use cookies to record information about your activities on the Site and to "remember" you when you return to the Site. The use of cookies is common and many websites use them to provide useful features to visitors. Some cookies remain on your computer until you delete them. Others, like session ID cookies, expire when you close your browser. You may set your browser setting to attempt to reject cookies and you may still use the Site. See the section "Online Tracking and your Choices" below for more information on how the Site may respond to your browser settings. We do not control the use of cookies by third parties. See the section on "Third-Party Providers" below.

**3.4 Pixels (aka web beacons/web bugs/java script).** Pixels are tiny graphics with a unique identifier that are used to track the online movements of web users. Unlike cookies, which are stored on a user's computer hard drive, pixels are small graphics that are about the size of the period at the end of the sentence that are embedded invisibly on web pages or in HTML-based emails. Our third-party analytics providers may place pixels on our web site that track what other web sites you visit (both before and after visiting the Site). Our third-party analytics providers use information obtained from pixels to help us improve our Site. We do not control the use of pixels by third parties. See the section on "Third-party Providers" below.

**3.5 Third-Party Providers.** We use third parties to help us operate and improve the Site. We may provide these third parties information we collect and they may collect information from you about your use of the Site. The information we share with third parties will, unless specifically noted otherwise in this Policy, be governed by this Policy and may only be used by those third parties to help us operate or improve the Site and to provide services to us. We do not control information collected by third parties and are not responsible for their use of that information. 

#### 4\. CHILDREN's PRIVACY

**4.1 General.** The School Course component of the Site is intended for users of all ages and we may collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13 ("child" or "children"). Any information collected from children is in compliance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act ("COPPA"). Below is a list of when we may collect information from children and how and when we will provide parental notice and seek parental consent in such cases. If we collect information from a child, we will only retain the information so long as reasonably necessary to fulfill a request, to allow the child to participate in an activity, to ensure the security of our services, or as required by law. If we discover that we have collected information from a child in a manner that is inconsistent with COPPA, we will either immediately seek parental consent or delete the information. We will never publicly post a child's personally identifiable information.

**4.2 Child Registration.** A child may register on the Site in order to take the course. During the registration process, we may ask the child to provide his or her birth date in order to verify age. If, during the registration process, we determine that a child is a child under the age of 13, we will ask for a parent or guardian email address before we collect any personally identifiable information from the child. Following verification, we may collect the child's name, email address, a user name, and password that they select.

**4.3 Teacher Consent.** If a child is using the course as part of a school-based activity, COPPA allows teachers or school administrators to provide consent for the collection of personally identifiable information from children.

**4.4 Child Quiz Results.** A child's quiz results may be shared with a child's course teacher if the child joins a classroom connected with a teacher account. 

**4.5 Email Contact with a Child.** BHP may, from time to time, send email to a child's email address in order to respond to inquiries or for account administration purposes. Following any such use of a child's email address, BHP will immediately delete the child's personally identifiable information. 

**4.6 Parental Control.** At any time, a parent or guardian may request that we delete the personally identifiable information that has been collected in connection with their child. When a parent makes such a request, it may lead to the termination of the child's account. Parents or guardians may make such a request by contacting us at: [info@bighistoryproject.com](mailto:info@bighistoryproject.com). When requesting removal of a child's personally identifiable information or cancellation of a child's account, parents or guardians should include the following information: Account ID (email address). To protect a child's privacy, we will take reasonable steps to verify a parent or guardian's identity prior to deleting a child's information.

#### 5\. ONLINE TRACKING AND YOUR CHOICES

As discussed above, because we track website usage information through the use of cookies, pixels and other tracking mechanisms, your selection of the "Do Not Track" option provided by your browser may not have any effect on our collection of cookie information. The only way to completely "opt out" of the collection of any information through cookies or other tracking technology is to actively manage the settings on your browser to delete and disable cookies and other tracking/recording tools. However, getting a "Do Not Track" signal to work as you might want is difficult. Using browsers as an example, not all tracking technologies can be controlled by browsers; unique aspects of your browser might be recognizable even if you disable a tracking technology; not all settings will necessarily last or be effective; even if a setting is effective for one purpose data still may be collected for another; and even if one website observes a "Do Not Track" signal, that website usually will not be able to control other websites.

#### 6\. INFORMATION SECURITY MEASURES

Personally identifiable information collected by the Site is stored in operating environments that are not available to the public. While we have mechanisms in place to safeguard your personal information after we receive it, no transmission of data over the internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure.

#### 7\. HOW WE USE YOUR INFORMATION

**7.1 General.** We may use your personally identifiable information for the purpose of communicating with you about the Big History Project, your account, or to provide you with other information that we think may be of interest to you. We may also use your name and email address to enable you to sign-in to certain portions of the Site or to personalize your experience on the Site.

**7.2 Account-related Emails.** We may send you emails about your account. For example, when you register, you will receive a welcome email. If our Site is temporarily unavailable, we may also send you an email notice. If you do not wish to receive these emails, you have the option to cancel your account. 

**7.3 Non-Personally Identifiable Information.** We may use anonymous information gathered from the Site for any lawful purpose, including but not limited to management and analysis of the Site, improvement of the Site, analyzing trends, and tracking users" movements around the Site.

**7.4 Information Retention.** In general, we will retain your information indefinitely, or as long as legally required or allowed. If you cancel your account, we may, but are not obligated to, delete information we have collected or obtained from third parties and we may continue to use and disclose it in accordance with this Policy. We may dispose of any information we collect in our discretion without notice, subject to applicable law. 

#### 8\. OUR INFORMATION SHARING PRACTICES

**8.1 General.** We will not sell or rent any of your personal information to third parties for marketing purposes. However, we may disclose your information to an affiliated entity or organization and to agents and service providers for the purpose of operating and improving the Site. Use of information by affiliated entities or organizations will be subject to this Privacy Policy or an agreement that is at least as restrictive as this Privacy Policy. For information on use of information by agents and service providers, see the "Third Party Providers" Section above.

**8.2 Research Purposes.** BHP is working with the University of Michigan to evaluate and improve the course. Teacher surveys and logs and student surveys, tests and writing samples are part of this evaluation and data submitted in those student materials are anonymously shared with the University of Michigan. By clicking "Register as a Teacher" or Register as a Student," you consent to BHP's collection and release of such information to the University of Michigan.

**8.3 Legal Requirements.** We reserve the right to disclose all information collected via the Site, internally or by third parties, for any lawful purpose or to prevent harm to us or others. For example and without limitation, in our discretion we may disclose information to government regulators, law enforcement authorities or alleged victims of identity theft.

**8.4 Insolvency and Business Transitions.** If we should ever file for bankruptcy or engage in a business transition such as a merger with another company or if we purchase, sell, or reorganize all or a part of our business or assets, we may disclose your personal Information, including to prospective or actual purchasers in connection with one of these transactions.

**8.5 Disclaimer.** We cannot ensure that all of your personally identifiable information will never be disclosed in ways not otherwise described in this Policy. For example, we may be required to disclose personal information to the government or third parties under certain circumstances, third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications, or users may abuse or misuse your personal information that they collect from the Site. We have taken all reasonable steps to ensure the security of your personally identifiable information. However, Nno transmission of data over the internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure.

#### 9\. LINKS

The Site contains links to other sites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices, the terms and conditions of use, or any of the content of such websites. The linked sites may collect personally identifiable information from you that is not subject to our control. The data collection practices of linked sites will be governed by that site's privacy policy.

#### 10\. CALIFORNIA MINORS

We may provide you the ability to post information on the Site. If you are a California resident who is under 18 and a registered user of the Site and you are unable to remove content or information you posted in a public area of the Site by following the instructions provided on the Site, you may request removal by using the contact information provided in the "Privacy Questions" section at the bottom of this Privacy Policy. When requesting removal please be specific about the information or content you want removed and provide the URL for each page on the Site where it is located. We are not required to remove any content or information that: (a) federal or state law requires us or a third party to maintain the content or information; (b) the content or information was not posted by you, the registered user; (c) we anonymize the content or information so that you cannot be identified; (d) you don"t follow our instructions for removing or requesting removal; or (e) you received compensation or other consideration for providing the content or information. REMOVAL OF YOUR POSTED CONTENT OR INFORMATION FROM THE SITE DOES NOT ENSURE COMPLETE OR COMPREHENSIVE REMOVAL OF THAT CONTENT OR INFORMATION FROM OUR SYSTEMS OR THE SYSTEMS OF OUR SERVICE PROVIDERS. We are not required to delete the content or information posted by you; our obligations under California law are satisfied so long as we anonymize the content or information or render it invisible to other users and the public. Also, some content and information you post that has been copied or reposted by a third party is outside of our control and will not be removed.

#### 11\. CALIFORNIA SHINE THE LIGHT LAW

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits California residents to request and obtain from us once a year, free of charge, a list of the third parties to whom we have disclosed personal information (as defined under that statute) of that California resident, for direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year and the categories of personal information that was disclosed to them. If you are a California resident and you wish to make such a request, you may contact us by using the contact information in the "Privacy Questions" section at the bottom of this Privacy Policy.

#### 12\. ACCESSING AND UPDATING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

If your personally identifiable information changes or if you would like to cancel your account, you may make such changes by contacting us at: info@bighistoryproject.com. 

If you are located in Australia, you are entitled to access personal information that we hold about you. If you request access to your personal information, in ordinary circumstances we will give you full access to your personal information. However, there may be some legal or administrative reasons to deny access. If we refuse your request to access your personal information, we will provide you with reasons for the refusal. A request for access can be made by contacting us at [info@bighistoryproject.com](mailto:info@bighistoryproject.com).

We take all reasonable steps to ensure that any personal information we collect and use is accurate, complete and up-to-date. To assist us in this, you need to provide true, accurate, current and complete information about yourself as requested, and properly update the information provided to us to keep it true, accurate, current and complete. Please contact us if you believe that the personal information is inaccurate or incomplete, and we will use all reasonable efforts to correct the information. 

#### 13\. PRIVACY QUESTIONS

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or other matters that relate to it, you may contact us by sending an email to: [info@bighistoryproject.com](mailto:info@bighistoryproject.com).

If you are located in Australia and you feel that your privacy has not been respected or that we have conducted ourselves inconsistently with this Privacy Policy, or for any other queries in relation to this Privacy Policy, please contact us at [info@bighistoryproject.com](mailto:info@bighistoryproject.com). 

We will investigate your queries and complaints within a reasonable period of time and will notify you of the outcome of our investigation.
